

AHMAD IBRAHIM

SENIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER

#aihrahim3546

aibrahim3546@gmail.com +60 14 239 8695 linkedin.com/in/aibrahim3546/ github.com/aibrahim3546

https://ahmadibrahim.io

PROFILE

I am software engineer with 5 years of experience working as a Frontend developer. My speciality are ReactJs and React

I am known as a person who focus on writing quality and high performance code. I am always focused on delivering the best products (pixel perfect) to the end users.

CORE SKILLS

- ReactJS
- React Native
- JavaScript
- TypeScript

TOOLS & TECHNOLOGY

- Jest (Testing)
- Cypress (Testing)
- S3 Storage (AWS)
- Secret Manager
- (AWS)
- CloudFlare
- Segment (Analytics)
- Atlassian (Jira, Confluence)

- NodeJS
- AWS
- MongoDB
- MySQL

- Codefresh (CI/CD)
- CloudFront (AWS) GitHub Actions
 - GitHub
 - Packages
 - Storybook
 - DataDog
 - Smartlook

REFERENCES

Lee Sian Loong Head of Technology - Revenue Monster

Stanley Yong CTO - Vettons

JK Teoh Ex-Staff Engineer - MoneyLion Engineering Director - Naluri

*contact information will be given upon request

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

MoneyLion (Mar 2021 - Present)

FinTech

- Finance App based in US (went IPO last year in NYSE).
- Introduced new architecture for frontend development.
- · Developed UI framework (for internal use) according to our design system. Hosted using private GitHub packages.
- · Lead the initiative to refactor and improve existing and legacy system.
- Worked on improving Developer Experience (DX) by enhancing the development workflow. Such as web preview for each pull request made.
- Improved core web vitals for all of all of our web projects.
- Implement e2e and unit test.
- Take initiative and execute things that improve the product or increase developer productivity.
- Mentor Jr. Developer.
- · Practice high engineering standard. Ensure all code are well tested before delivered to end users.
- Manage CI/CD pipelines.

Frontend Developer

TNG Digital (Nov 2020 - Mar 2021)

Fintech (TnG ewallet)

- No 1 e-wallet in Malaysia. A joint venture between Ant Financial (Alibaba) and Touch n' Go Malaysia.
- Lead developer for new product (Insurance renewal)
- Practice Test driven development (TDD).
- Ensure code delivered to end users are well tested with unit testing.

Frontend Developer

Vettons (June 2019 - Oct 2020)

Technology/E-commerce

- Lead Developer for main product (Vettons App React Native)
- · Setup code standard (followed Airbnb engineering guidlines) and ensure all engineers followed the practice.
- Manage App Store & Play Store release. For both android and iOS.
- · Worked with Augmented Reality (AR) and Speech to text technology
- Mentor Jr. Developer

Associate Full Stack Developer

Revenue Monster Sdn Bhd (Dec 2017 - March 2019)

FinTech

- Revenue Monster is a FinTech company that focus on payment gateway.
- Worked on a new Project (WeTix) with minimal guidance form seniors/lead.
- · Maintain and develop new features for WeTix.
- Manage production deployment for WeTix.

EDUCATION

Asia Pacific University (2015 - 2017)

Diploma in Electric and Electronic Engineering

SOFT SKILLS

• Critical Thinking • UI/UX Sense • Team Player • Leadership